

#### **CONTACT**

Phone: +49 175 / 649 50 50

Mail:

verenatraubmail@gmail.com

Web:

verenatraub.netlify.app







## **SKILLS**

# Hands-on experience in:

- HTML & CSS
- SASS & Handlebars
- JavaScript (ES6)
- React
- ExpressJS
- NodeJS
- Leaflet
- MongoDB & Mongoose
- Axios
- Github, Gitlab, Jira

# On my current learning & project list:

- TypeScript
- NextJS
- AWS / AWS CDK

#### **Toolbox:**

Scrum & Kanban

# Languages:

German - Mother tongue English - fluent Polish - basic skills

Jagstzell, January 2022

# **VERENA TRAUB**

Rookie-Developer and Junior Cloud Engineer with an agile skillset who discovered her passion for programming - and after several years in tech recruiting turned this into a carreer.

After a successfully completed coding bootcamp and some months in Web Development, I am now starting into the Cloud with a focus on AWS and serverless.

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# since 01/2022

Junior Consultant Cloud Engineering - superluminar GmbH, Hamburg

#### 06/2021 - 11/2021

# Junior Frontend Developer (Freelance) - aiconix GmbH, Hamburg

- Supporting the development team on their real-time transcription sytem
- Project: Refactoring and further improvements on the "Emergency Button" feature to turn subtitles off and on during live streaming
- TechStack: NextJS, DraftJS, Typescript

# Since 03/2017

**Founder, CEO & Lead Recruiter** - yngage GmbH, Hamburg & Baden-Württemberg

- Interim Management as Tech Recruiter and Scrum Master for clients such as it agile, ThoughtWorks Spain, Equal Experts, aiconix or For Sale Digital
- Workshops and trainings about recruiting, Employer Branding or agile HR / agile recruiting

#### 12/2013 - 02/2017

## Freelane Consultant & Interim Manager, Hamburg

- Interim Management as Tech Recruiter and Scrum Master for clients such as SinnerSchrader, XING, ThoughtWorks Deutschland or Brandslisten
- Workshops and trainings about recruiting, Employer Branding or agile HR / agile recruiting

# 01/2011 - 11/2013

# **Recruiting Manager** - CoreMedia AG, Hamburg

- Tech-Recruiting
- Employer Branding and HR marketing
- Contact person for managers and employees

## 12/2008-12/2010

# Omikron Data Quality GmbH, Pforzheim

- 11/2009 12/2010: HR Manager with focus on further developing the HR function as well as tech recruiting
- 12/2008 10/2009: Assistant of the CEO and HR Management

## **EDUCATION**

#### 10/2020 - 04/2021

# Full-Stack Web-Development Bootcamp - Ironhack (remote)

- Frontend technologies: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React
- Backend technologies: ExpressJS, NodeJS, MongoDB, Mongoose, Axios
- Design and development of 3 different projects (see below)

#### 10/2015 Certified Scrum Master (CSM)

training by it-agile (Hamburg), certification by Scrum Alliance (remote)

#### 02/2007 - 08/2008

**Studies in Business Administration -** Akademia Ekonomiczna w Poznaniu, Poznan (Polen)

- Final degree: German diploma and Polish magister in Business Administration
- Final grade: 1,6
- Focus disciplines: Business Informatics, Marketing, International Business, Business English

# 10/2004 - 02/2007

Studies in Business Administration - TU Bergakademie Freiberg, Freiberg

# **PROJECTS**

# **EyeBird** - an app for bird lovers

Tech Stack: JavaScript, React, ExpressJS, NodeJS, MongoDB, Mongoose,

Leaflet, Axios, SASS, React-Bootstrap, HTML & CSS

Github: <a href="https://github.com/vtrHH/nature-app">https://github.com/vtrHH/nature-app</a>

Demo: <a href="https://eyebird.netlify.app/">https://eyebird.netlify.app/</a>

# Mooseician - a marketplace for musicians

Tech Stack: JavaScript, ExpressJS, NodeJS, Handlebars, MongoDB, Mongoose,

SASS, Bootstrap, HTML & CSS

Github: <a href="https://github.com/vtrHH/musicians-app">https://github.com/vtrHH/musicians-app</a>
Demo: <a href="https://mooseician.herokuapp.com/">https://mooseician.herokuapp.com/</a>

#### Mask Game - an online game

Tech Stack: HTML & CSS, HTML Canvas, JavaScript

Github: https://github.com/vtrHH/ironhack-project1-mask-game

Demo: <a href="https://verena-mask-game.netlify.app/">https://verena-mask-game.netlify.app/</a>

More projects at <u>verenatraub.netlify.app</u>

#### **ABOUT ME**

## Since 07/2017

Mother of a wonderful son

#### 03/2011 - 02/2022

**Lecturer, Career Center of the University of Hamburg,** Hamburg as well as remote

#### 02/2016 - 01/2022

#### Organizer of the Agile meets HR Meetup, Hamburg

(since 2020 with additional groups in Berlin and Munich)